

Ajith Amarnath

Module Lead - Software development

Phone: 7904949080

Address: Madurai South, Tamil Nadu, India

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ajith-k-a-18b71713b/

Email: kuttenajith1998@gmail.com

5.10 years of experience designing and building responsive web design and mobile apps. Proficient with CSS and JS Frameworks, with extensive knowledge of UX and user psychology. Notable achievements include boosting the conversion rate of an existing website by 94% with improved code and design.

EXPERIENCE

Celsior Technologies

October 2023 - Present

Module Lead

- · Design and implement software modules, ensuring alignment with overall project architecture.
- Involve in developing the complete front end development using HTML, JavaScript and CSS. Work with multiple onshore teams.
- Collaborate with QA teams to develop and execute test plans.

CodeCraft Technologies Pvt Ltd, Bengaluru

August 2022 - October 2023

Senior Engineer

- Worked with Node Packet Manager(npm), Dynamo DB and used React and VUE JS library functions and GraphQL for the logical implementation part at client side for all the application.
- Worked with Vuex for the state management and deals with client directly for the scrum and sprint meetings Make sure sprint goals are achieved on a date.
- Coordinate with cross-functional teams to define project requirements and deliverables.

Tanisha Systems, Inc, Madurai South

April 2021 - August 2022

Application Developer

- Developed non-functional HTML5, CSS3 pages from the mock-ups and involved in UI review with UI architect and Business units
- Worked in python for the back end, supported team to achieve goals on date and deals with client directly.

Zencode Group, Chennai

December 2018 - April 2021

Frontend Developer

- Demonstrated expertise in HTML5, CSS3, object-orientated JavaScript and large JavaScript applications.
- Handled Interns to instruct python fundamentals and things.

EDUCATION

KLNCE (Anna University)

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Science

January 2015 - December 2019

Grade: A

SKILLS

HTML 5 CSS 3 Bootstrap v5 JavaScript TypeScript React 18 VUE 3 Node.js Next.js Polymer.js keystone.js axios python JIRA Jenkins Mantis Unit Testing API Integration websocket AWS SQL Firebase MongoDB GIT Bitbucket postgresql golang

PROJECTS

Cox Prosight, React js - London, United Kingdom

https://www.coxprosight.com/

- Took ownership of the Safety module and implemented it with high quality. Initiated Leverage discussion, and modified device control feature, which improved Analytics for inventory and Utilization.
- Provided solutions for Map-related Leverage bugs. Made sure sprint goals are achieved on the date. Participated in planning and sprint demos.

CIRCULAR-CITY(UI), London, United Kingdom

https://www.circularcity.asia/

- Took ownership of the UI with responsiveness and designed it with high quality. Provided solutions for media query-related bugs. Made sure sprint goals are achieved on the date.
- Worked in python for the back end, supported team to achieve goals on date and deals with client directly.

Telematic VIA Motors, React js - United States

https://www.viamotors.com/vehicles/

- Took me ownership of the motor tree, vehicle list view module and Took owne implemented it with high quality. Provided solutions for relationship-tree fix.
- Made sure sprint goals are achieved on the date. Participated in planning and sprint demos.

HELPZ, Vue js - United Kingdom

• Took ownership of the Admin end and implemented it with high quality. Made sure sprint goals are achieved on the date. Participated in planning and sprint demos.

IGoalZero, React JS, golang - United States

https://www.igoalzero.com/

- Took ownership of the Print Details module and implemented both Generic Print and Custom Print with high quality. Suggested Picky component which improved essential fixes of the dropdown that we have in the project.
- Completed CUSTOM PRINT module with PDFME library in Auditor end to preview and send or email the report. Provided solutions for library and PDF related bugs. Make sure sprint goals are achieved on a date.

CSIDI - IBM, United States

https://www.csidi.org/

- The Cultural Society of International Diplomats in Israel (CSIDI) provides spouses of the diplomatic corps an opportunity to meet, learn and enjoy all that the nations of the world have to offer through music, dance, art, fashion and food.
- Took ownership of the Blue Pages and implemented it with high quality. Made sure sprint goals are achieved on the date. Participated in planning and sprint demos directly with clients.

FBFS - Vue JS, golang - United Kingdom

https://www.fbfs.com/

- FBL Financial Group, Inc. (FFG), is a holding company with the purpose to protect livelihoods and futures. Operating under the consumer brand name Farm Bureau Financial Services, its affiliates offer a broad range of life insurance, annuity and investment products distributed by multiline exclusive Farm Bureau agents.
- Took ownership of the Admin end and implemented it with high quality. Made sure sprint goals are achieved on the date. Participated in planning and sprint demos.

LANGUAGES

English (Full professional proficiency), **Tamil** (Full professional proficiency), **Sourastra** (Native), **Hindi** (Limited working proficiency)